Hafsa Ahmed

Front End Developer

Phone: +20-111-341-7881

Email: hafsamubarak96@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <u>in/hafsa-ahmed96/</u>

GitHub: /hafsamubarak
Behance: /hafsaahmed3

SUMMARY

Ambitious Junior Front End Developer brings enthusiasm and detailed understanding of various programming languages to web page planning, development and maintenance. Experience designing and developing sites from concept to roll out. Foundational grasp of various CSS and HTML options, plugins, development platforms, frameworks ex. Angular, React. Goal-driven individual with excellent grasp of Agile Methodologies.

Graduate at Information Technology Institute "ITI" of Front End development and Cross platform track.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

General	Tools	Languages	Platform / Frameworks
Web development	Visual StudioCode	HTML5, CSS3	Angular 12
Front End Development	GIT	SASS.	React JS.
UI/UX Design		JavaScript (es6).	Bootstrap
		TypeScript.	MongoDB
			Firebase
			GraphQL

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer .. May 22 - Present

Devindu

- Responsible for Design new components "ex: Eskedo: it's a project that main purpose it to allow the user to design an online website".
- Review and fix the existing components.
- Make sure that the design is responsive and is pixel-perfect to the prototype.

Front End Developer "Intern" in ITI .. AUG 21 - DEC 21

• Involved in requirement gathering, analysis, design and development of the application.

• Established user interface design standards, internationalization considerations, framework guide to enhance developments autonomy.

• Developed dynamic and static web pages using HTML5, CSS 3, JavaScript and Angular 12.

Sales Engineer ...JUNE 2020 - AUG 2020

AIB Solar Company

- · Analyzing and solving clients problems.
- · Sell and promote products using solid arguments to existing and prospective customers.

Arduino Instructor .. Jul 2017 - MARCH 2020 "PART TIME"

• Trained more than 50 students on Arduino IDE and implemented different projects.

EDUCATION

Professional Diploma of Front End and Cross
 Platform ... Aug 15 2021 - DEC 15 2021

Information Technology Institute "ITI"

- Course of Web Design .. April 2020 May 2020
 National Telecommunication Institute "NTI",
- Course of Back-end Development using PHP ... MAY 2020 - JUNE 2020
 National Telecommunication Institute "NTI",
- Course of Career Development ...JUL 2020 AUG 2020
 National Telecommunication Institute "NTI", *Top Ranked graduate*.
- Bachelor of Electronics and Communication Engineering, .. SEP 2014 AUG 2019

 High Institute of Engineering and technology, Luxor,

Accumulated grade: *Very Good* - Graduation Project "Smart Gloves for deafs and dumbs Grade: *Very Good*.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

1. My Professional Portfolio:

Technology used: (Angular12, Bootstrap).

Site : hafsa-ahmed-portofolio

2. CliniDo medical website:

Objective: Book a medical consultation online.

Technology used: (Angular 12, Firebase, Angular Material, Bootstrap).

Site: clinido-ce15d.web.app/

3. To Do-List for WEBW company:

Objective: The user has to sign up to be able to add his own To-dos. The user can edit and delete the to dos.

Technology used: (Angular 13, Firebase Authentication, Bootstrap).

Site: webw-crud-app

4. UI/UX design for WEBW company:

Technology used: (Bootstrap).

Site: webw-ui-ux

5. Admin Dashboard For ClinDo App:

Objective: make the app fully dynamic by pushing the variables through the dashboard.

Technology used: (React JS, Bootstrap, Firebase)

Site: clinido-dashboard.herokuapp.com/

6. React Movie App:

Objective: Get all movies from the API and the user can see movie details and add/remove movies from their favorites.

Site: movie-app-with-react-js.herokuapp.com

7. Voice Recognition App for children using Vanilla JavaScript:

Objective: This is an educational app for children to learn words by speaking, listening to different words and repeating them.

Site: Voice-Recognition-with-vanilla-JavaScript